When you decide how to spend your marketing budget,
在决定如何分配营销预算时
you want to focus on some of your best customers,
应该注重在获取最理想的客户群
customers who will stay with you for the long-term,
也就是会长期关注并购买你的产品的那些客户
who will continue to generate revenue for the company longer than say,
他们会长期持续给公司带来收入
a customer who finds a cheaper deal somewhere else and leaves your website.
而不是那些找到其他更便宜的产品之后 就不再光顾你的网站的客户
In other words, you want to identify your high-value customer,
换言之 你应该分辨哪些是高价值客户
so that you can focus on bringing in more of these customers.
然后将重心放在吸引更多这样的客户
Think of it this way: Your goal is for every dollar you spend on
这样想 — 你的目标是在营销方面每花一元
your marketing efforts to give you a higher rate of
都希望它能够给你带来更高回报率
return and generate revenue multiple times over.
而且能够反复带来收入
How do you go about doing that?
如何着手实现这一点 ?
You use a business metric called lifetime value of a customer.
可以运用 "客户生命周期价值" 这个业务指标
To calculate lifetime value,
要计算客户生命周期价值
let's cover a few key concepts.
就涉及到一些关键概念
Again, make sure you make a note of the terminology and definitions.
要注意做好笔记哦 记下术语和含义
They are going to get slightly complicated,
概念会有点复杂
but we will walk through each of them one by one.
我们会逐个讲解的
So, keep in mind we want to be able to estimate how much revenue we can expect
首先记住 这里的目的是 把眼光放远
to earn per customer as far into the future as we can.
再来预期从每位客户身上赚取多少收入
To calculate this, we need to take into account a lot of
因此 需要考虑许多不同的指标和数据
different metrics and data to create a single LTV metric.
才能计算出客户生命周期价值 (英文简称 LTV) 指标
First, purchase cycle is a time period that
首先 购买周期是指
depicts the general frequency with which your products are purchased.
通常每隔多久会购买你的产品
At Udacity, if we start a new nano degree class every two weeks,
以优达学城为例 如果我们每隔两星期开展一期纳米学位课程
two weeks would be the purchase cycle.
购买周期就是两星期
Total sales revenue per cycle is the revenue
每周期总销售收入是指
earned from all customers per purchase cycle.
每个购买周期从所有客户赚取的收入总额
Number of sales per purchase cycle is the number of
每个购买周期销售量是指
times your average customer buys during the purchase cycle.
在一个购买周期内 客户购买产品的次数
Cost per acquisition, you've seen this before.
每次获取成本 CPA 这个之前已经详细讲解了
It's a total cost of marketing and sales divided by the number of new leads.
是营销销售总成本除以新潜在客户人数
With me this far, feel free to pause the video or [inaudible] ,
目前为止 对于我所说的内容
review, and think about what I've said this far.
大家可以按暂停或者回看 思考消化一下
Next, we have expectation retention time.
接下来 预期保留客户时间是指
This is the amount of time you expect to retain the customer.
你预期能够保留客户多久
This is measured in terms of purchase cycles,
这是按多少个购买周期来衡量的
what we covered right at the top of this list.
也就是刚刚说的第一点
So, if we expect a customer to be retained for a year given a two-week purchase cycle,
举例来说 如果预期保留客户一年 以两星期为一个购买周期
then we have an ERT of about 26.
则预期保留客户时间 (英文简称 ERT) 则为 26
Average sales revenue is the revenue you earn from
平均销售收入是指
the average customer per transaction during the cycle.
购买周期内平均每次交易从客户赚取的收入
This is the total customer revenue divided by the number of purchases in the cycle.
计算方式是 购买周期内 总客户收入除以购买次数
Profit margin per customer is the percentage of sales that has turned into profits.
客户利润是指 记入利润的销售额比例
Again, feel free to pause the video here and process what I've covered this far.
可以暂停视频 思考消化一下我所讲的内容
Next, we have one last thing to do,
说完这些概念
calculate the lifetime value.
如何计算客户生命周期价值呢 ?
Lifetime value is the average sale times the number of
计算客户生命周期价值 要把平均销售额乘以…
repeated sales times expected retention time times profit margin.
…反复销售次数 乘以预期保留客户时间 再乘以利润率
Essentially, this is the net profit you can attribute to
得出的价值可以视为
the customer over the length of their relationship with the company.
一位顾客与公司保持消费关系期间 给公司带来的净利润
Let's do this in Excel in the next video.
我们将在下一个视频利用 Excel 范例进行讲解